Hello everyone, welcome to another episode of Trust Talk.
Today we are discussing in detail a very good news for NRIs or Indians living abroad who want to take a new health insurance or transfer their existing health insurance to another company. Yes, for the
first time in health insurance, NRA
customers are being
given a discount of 40% to 42% on the annual premium. That too for
all renewals. To understand
which products and
features, terms and conditions are being offered by the leading insurance companies in India,
try to watch the video without missing any. Before entering the video, a
quick introduction about myself.
My name is Sanoj Lal, a certified
financial consultant. We bring
all the news related to insurance to
you only after studying and researching it thoroughly. If
you have not yet subscribed to this channel called Trust Talk,
Please Subscribe to the
Channel to Get Right Information at Right Time Be Healthy
and
Wealthy Leading general insurance
companies in India like ICCI Lombard and HDFC
ERGO are offering up to
42%
discount on annual premium to NRI customers. Before going into the product
and details, terms and conditions, let
us
understand the benefits of NRIs taking a health insurance in India. First point is Low
treatment cost. Although we say that
medical treatment costs in India are
increasing day by day, when
compared to foreign countries,
our medical cost is very, very
low. Even in the largest economic power, the United States,
one of the main reasons for going bankrupt is its medical bills.
Second point is Quality
treatment at convenience. To get
a specialty doctor appointment in Canada or any foreign country, it
takes a minimum of six months, but in
our country  Ayyathan Doorath is
also far from competitive in terms of the
quality of
healthcare system in our country. Now let's come
back to the main topic. Let's understand the product and features, terms and conditions of
HDFC
Ergo and ICICI Loan Part, which offer NRI discounts, through a
detailed
comparison.
This discount is currently being given to NRIs in HDFC Ergo's Optima Secure health insurance plan and in ICCI
Ombud's latest
health insurance plan called Elevate.
We are only covering the top unique selling points of both these plans in this video.
We have covered the detailed comparison of these two plans in a previous
video. To
know more about this product,
please keep on watching that video.
We are giving the link here in the description
box. HDFC
Ergo's Optimus  Zwicker's Top
USB is Forex coverage four
times of base sum insured
coverage. For example, a person who takes a sum insured of ₹10 lakhs after two
years, his total
insurance cover is ₹40
lakhs. If he takes ICCI Lombard's Elevate
plan, its Top
USB is Infinity Coverage, Power Booster
and Jump Start etc.
Infinity coverage means infinite
insurance cover. Power
Booster means 10
times of guaranteed cumulative bonus. Jump Start means certain
listed pre-existing
diseases will
get insurance cover through this rider from the 31st day.
Next, we will discuss the
terms and conditions for getting NRI discount. As
mentioned in the beginning, this discount is available only to
NRI customers.
HDFC  If we choose Ergo,
all the insured
members must be customers holding NRI status.
Otherwise, if
we are ICCI Lombard, then if
only one of our insureds holds NRI status, then
this discount will be available.
Next Point is for fresh and porting
situations.
People who want to take a new policy or
those who want to change their existing policy to any of the plans we discuss here.
Next Point Discounts are for people who want to get
NRI discount through Optimus Secure. Up to
40%
discount is available.
Elevate plan. NRI discount is
25% plus CIBIL score discount plus
renewal discount all put together.
Total discount up to 425% is
available. Next Point
is for
NRIs at the time of renewal.  The plan
offers discounts but the condition is that all the
insured should hold NRI status. In case of
Optimus Secure
plan, all the members should be customers holding
NRI status at the time of policy renewal.
Similarly, no
claim should be reported in India during the renewal period. If you are
taking another As Elevate plan, any insured should
hold NRI status. Any of the insured members in the plan should be holding NR status. The
next point at the time of renewal
is the document requirements. To
get NR discount in HDFC Ergo plan,
we need to submit NRI
declaration, passport, visa and bank statement. To
get ICI Lombard discount in Elevate plan,
we need to submit passport
and visa copy. The next
most important point is the premium
and  Pricing is the normal premium of these two plans and the
premium discount we get due to NRI discount. Let
us clearly understand that for
a family with age category 39, 34, 10 and four age groups, the
basic coverage is 10 lakhs. If
we take HDFC
Ergo Optimus Secure, the normal
premium is coming to
33278. In this, we apply NRI discount and after that it is coming to just
19967 rupees. Same age category, same
coverage. If we look at ICICI Lombard Elevate
plan, the normal premium is
2377 rupees after applying NRI
discount plus sibile score discount. The
premium is coming to just
14903 rupees per person. Here comes my
personal recommendation HDFC Ergo.  According to the
latest report of ICI Lombard IR for 2023-24, the
two leading insurance
companies with the highest ICR incurred claim ratio are HDFC ERGO Company's
ICR is
8098% and ICICI Lombard's ICR is
785%, which are the highest in the
industry. This is the first time in India that
health insurance companies are
giving such a discount on annual premium to NRI customers, without making any
difference in the base product or service. Normally,
these
companies are giving such a discount because the chances of NRI customers getting a claim in India are very low. To know more about the
NRI scheme discount
product and features that we discussed today,
you
can call or whatsapp on the number given below. Before the video ends,
a reminder: Insurance is a subject
matter of solicitation. Before choosing any
insurance product, it is important to read the terms and conditions of
that
product.  Please
read and understand the conditions clearly.
Also, if you have not yet subscribed to this channel called Trust Talk,
please subscribe to the
channel to get the right information at the right time. Until
next time,
I am signing off
on Sanoj Slash
[Music]